所有乘客请注意
Attention, all passengers.
室外温度
The temperature outside...
是零下121.9摄氏度
...is minus 121.9 degrees Celsius.
我们即将到达芝加哥 我们生命循环的出发点
As we approach Chicago, mile zero of our cycle of life,
做好准备
be prepared to brace.
我们都受到我们选择的困扰
We're all haunted by our choices.
我们登上列车时所做出的个人选择
The personal choices we all made when we boarded this train.
以及让我们走到那天的集体选择
And the collective choices that brought us to that day.
数十年来做出的选择
Choices made over decades,
即便当我们知道气候变化不是传说
even when we knew climate change was real.
最后 是我的选择 挟持这座方舟
And finally my own choice to pirate this ark
对你们所有人撒谎
and lie to you all...
让我们走到了现在
which has brought us to where we are now.
愿我们所有人在接下来都更加清醒地
May we all move forward with greater awareness
认识到我们所做的选择
of the choices that we make.
我们列车一心
We are one train.
今天 列车选择了改变
And today that train chooses change.
我在此将雪国列车的统治权
I hereby relinquish governance of Snowpiercer
交给叛军
to the rebel forces.
这是我们的循环
These are our revolutions,
994节车厢
994 cars long.
雪国列车的公民
Citizens of Snowpiercer...
我是安德烈·莱顿
...my name is Andre Layton.
雪国列车
第一季 第十集[季终]
好 我们开工吧
Okay. Let's get to work.
-重置一下5 4 3号线 哈维  -好
-Alright, can you reset line 5, 4, and 3 for me, Javi?  -Alright.
我们伤得不轻
We took a beating.
是啊
No shit.
有37节电池车下线了
So, we've got 37 battery cars offline,
可能需要12小时充电
probably 12 hours to recharge.
我们电力不足了
We're running low on juice.
我把自己全天候锁在这里之前
Before I lock myself up here full time,
我还得去做件事
there's something I need to go do.
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
不能
No.
你已经帮忙了
You already have.
就是...
It's just, um  --
有件事我已经推迟很久了
It's something I've put off for a long time.
我们付出了沉重代价 迈尔斯
We paid a heavy price, Miles.
最后的澳洲人他们 他们在后车
The Last Aussie and the guys, they're downtrain.
他们想见你
They want to see you.
奶奶也在那里
Mama Grande's there, too.
我们失去乔茜了 是吧
We lost Josie, didn't we?
是的
Yeah, we did.
她爱你 迈尔斯
She loved you, Miles.
好吗 她也爱我 她...
Okay? She loved me, too. She was  --
她为我们付出了一切
She was all in for all of us.
你知道车尾人怎么纪念离世吧
Hey, you know how a Tailie marks a passing, right?
一起铭记
Together.
不遗忘任何人
No one forgotten.
不让任何人孤独
No one alone.
没错
That's right.
她会很为你骄傲的
She'd have been so proud of you.
好了 我知道情况并不理想
Alright, I know conditions are not ideal,
但我现在要做些解释
but I'm gonna explain some things right now.
好了 听好 接下来是这样的
Okay, listen up! This is how this is going to go!
司闸员和叛军将负责管事
The Brakemen and the rebel army will be in charge
直到 当选委员会建立宪法
until an elected council can create a constitution
成立代议政府
for a representative government.
叛军在打劫 闯入舱室
The rebel army is looting and breaking into cabins!
对 是发生了打劫
Yes, there has been some looting,
但现在我们完全控制住了 好吗
but we are in total control now, okay?
我向大家承诺
And I promise you all have my word
不会再有复仇了
that there will be no reprisals.
这场战争结束了 现在要开始工作
This war is over. Now the work begins.
我们要让雪国列车动起来
We need to get Snowpiercer up and running.
农业区的人不在这 因为他们所有人
Ag-Sec isn't here because every single one of them's
都在岗位上坚守着我们食物来源
back there guarding our food supply.
-我知道 我正努力  -你觉得当你杀了
-I know. I'm working  ---What do you expect
保持秩序的安保人员后会出现什么情况
when you murder the security forces who kept order?
他们用毒气杀我们 他们处决囚犯
They killed us with gas! They executed prisoners!
人们需要看到改变 而不是秩序 露丝
The people need to see change, not order, Ruth.
我们不会再截断手臂
We're not taking any arms.
我们不会再把人放进抽屉
We're not putting people in drawers.
我们现在靠自己了
We look to ourselves now.
你们各位都是协会的领袖
Alright, now, you people, you are the leaders of the Guilds.
没错 你们是各部门的头
Yes, you are Department Heads.
你们是乘客代表
You're Passenger Representatives.
我们对每个人的信息都很简单明了
Our message to everyone right now is very simple  --
列车现在是你们的了
This train is yours now.
今晚我们会经过芝加哥
Tonight we pass through Chicago...
那是一切开始的地方
...where all of this started.
跟你们的爱人纪念这一刻吧
Mark it with your loved ones.
这是全新的一圈
It's a brand-new revolution.
真是胡扯
This is some bullshit.
这么多人里竟然是你 你支持这一切
You of all people, you're supporting this?
你知道 如果乘客服务部
You know, this will be a lot easier
能跟我们朝同一个方向走 一切都会简单很多 露丝
if Hospitality is paddling in the same direction, Ruth.
那是什么方向
Which direction is that?
乌托邦式的胡言乱语永远不能让这列车团结
Utopian twaddle will never hold this train together.
这里是怎么回事
What's going on here?
这是什么情况
Uh, what is this?
你怎么进来的 派克先生
How'd you get in, Mr. Pike?
我弄到了一个头等厢的芯片
I procured a custom First Class chip.
现在这东西到处都是
They're suddenly everywhere these days.
小莱 这是
LJ, this is, uh...
我不知道这些人是谁 但这是安妮
I don't know who these people are, but this is Annie.
安妮
Mm. Annie.
这是特伦斯 保洁员之王
And this is Terence, King of the Janitors.
爽 真是爽歪歪 对吧
Oh, yeah! How was that, huh?
在头等厢的床上来一发
Having a go in a First Class bed, right?
下一个是谁
Now, who's next here?
好
Okay.
不
No.
这里有你喜欢的吗
You see anyone you like?
也许你能给你的鸡巴收藏再添一个
Maybe you can add a dick to your collection.
出去
Oh! Get out!
请出去
Please get out.
我家人死了 我要你们都离开
My family is dead, and I need you to leave.
你们都给我离开 拜托了
I need you to leave, please. Please.
你应该对反抗军更慷慨些
You should be more generous to the resistance.
你又不是反抗军
You are not the resistance.
你出卖了他们 他出卖了你们所有人
You sold them out. He sold you all out!
这里现在是我的车厢了 懂吗
This is all my carriage now, okay?
你没有朋友 小莱
You have no friends, LJ.
这年头 没有朋友的人就是穷人
And these days, someone with no friends is poor,
这意味着我是富人
and that makes me rich!
甚高频波段收到了什么
What's the VHF picking up?
我今早听到一阵短暂的声音
Oh, I heard a blip of that this morning.
是列车里传来的
It's from the train.
音乐吗 哪里来的
Music? Where's it coming from?
农业区的无线或列车后方的无线电吗
Ag-Sec wireless or one of the HAM sets downtrain?
他们还在放广播节目吗
Those guys are still broadcasting?
我还以为他们不做了呢
I thought they'd given up.
真奇怪
So weird.
该死
Shit.
怎么了
What happened?
卫星信号消失了
We just lost the satellite feed.
别担心 我来处理
Don't worry. I'm on it.
我们需要它来定位信号
We need it back to locate the signal.
你总算准备好了
You're finally ready now.
你一直都在逃避
You've been avoiding this for a long time.
现在我知道原因了
Now I know why.
雪国列车是你的主意
Snowpiercer was your idea.
为了让它运行 我做过一些不当的事
I've done questionable things to keep her going.
你折磨人们
You tortured people.
截断他们的手臂
You took their arms.
还害死了147个最后的地球人
And sent 147 of the last souls on Earth to death.
我得背负这些苟活
I have to live with that.
你来这是因为对一件事耿耿于怀
You're here because there's something that you can't live with.
听
Listen.
让暖风唤醒你的记忆
Let the warm breeze bring your memory...
你过往的气息
...the scent of your past...
黑土
dark earth...
湿岩
wet rocks...
高草
and tall grass.
想起那时
Remember when life...
生命遍及你所看之处 所经之地
...was everywhere you looked, everywhere you walked.
生命紧抱着你 赋予你奇迹
It cradled you, fed you wonder,
让你成为现在的你
made you who you are.
再倾听雪国列车
Now hear Snowpiercer.
感受轨道
Feel the track.
金属的摩擦碰撞
Metal on metal.
永动机的流动
The flow of your Engine Eternal...
它的血脉给予所有还活着的生命力量
...her veins bringing power to everything that's still alive.
在你的脑海里 门一扇扇地打开
In your mind, a door opens on another door opening.
你走进自己内心
You're stepping into yourself...
越走越深
stepping deeper.
你往更深处走去
You're going deeper...
直到最后...
until finally...
♪ I've got your picture ♪
♪ That you gave to me ♪
♪ And it's signed with love ♪
♪ Just like it used to be ♪
艾莉珊德拉
Alexandra.
♪ The only thing different ♪
♪ The only thing new ♪
♪ I've got your picture ♪
是什么
What is it?
你看到了什么
我的女儿 我的女儿
My daughter. My daughter.
为了列车 我牺牲了我的女儿
I sacrificed my daughter for this train.
当时我只顾着工作
I put my work first.
即便在最后 我还在岗位上
Even at the end, I didn't stop.
我没去她那 因为确信他们能上车
I didn't go to her, so certain that they'd be there.
然而
But then...
列车出发了 但他们没有
then the train was leaving, and  --and they weren't.
然后
And...
我留在了列车上
I stayed with the train.
再往前走
Go further.
如果艾莉克斯在这里
If Alex was here...
你想对她说什么
...what would you want to say to her?
我想你
I miss you.
我需要你
I need you.
还有...
And...
用手抚摸我的脸颊
Put your hand on my cheek.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
只要能再抱抱你 我愿意付出一切
I would give anything just to hold you again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真对不起
她看起来像...
She looks like a  --
我说不好 像个星座
I don't know  --like a constellation.
你觉得宝宝是女孩吗
You think it's a she?
我没多想 就这么脱口而出了 你呢
I didn't think. I just...said it. You?
男孩
Boy.
所以以后就是这样了 对吗
So that's how this is gonna go, huh?
是的
Yeah.
我想是吧
I guess so.
不再以我们为中心
It's not about us anymore.
我们不重要了 现在她才是重点
We're not important. It's about her now.
没错
Yeah.
或者是他
Or him.
那么 我们该如何做
So, how do we do this?
发生了这么多事
After everything.
乔茜也去世了
After Josie.
我们永远不可能成为以前梦想的家庭
We're never gonna be the family we dreamed of.
但我们会找到办法
But we'll find a way.
他们洗劫了家禽区 毁坏了水产区
They raided Poultry, damaged Aquaculture,
偷走了半车厢生菜
stole half a car of lettuce.
他们想拿什么就拿什么
They're taking anything they want.
现在我面临严重的供应链问题
Now I have serious supply-chain issues,
你还想要整辆列车的人都能摄入相等的卡路里
and you want the whole train to have equal calories?
这是你要优先考虑的事
That's your first priority.
我们少了16个熟练工人
We're down 16 trained men.
已经48小时没合过眼
We're going on 48 hours no sleep.
谢谢你的努力 珍珠
Oh, thank you for your efforts, Jinju.
好了 我该走了
Okay, this is where I go
让你们单独讨论一下供应链问题
and I let you two discuss your supply-chain issues.
我不明白如此弥天大谎你怎么能瞒着我
I just don't understand how you could just keep such a big lie from me.
还瞒着整辆列车
And the whole train.
因为不瞒着只会变成这样
Because this is the alternative.
如果人们需要一个威尔福德 何不给他们希望
And if the people needed a Wilford, why deny them that hope?
拜托 提尔
Come on, Till.
你真的宁愿孤独无援吗
Would you really rather be alone?
我并非孤独一人
I'm not alone.
我有和我统一战线的兄弟姐妹
I've got my sisters and brothers I stood with
以及对雪国列车
and a responsibility to Snowpiercer
前所未有的责任感
I have never felt before.
这么说我们终于意见一致了 列车最重要
So we finally agree. The train comes first.
你知道在雪国列车上分手的人会怎么说
You know what they say when you break up on Snowpiercer.
"回头"见
See you around.
乘客服务部
你是来退位的
So you've come to abdicate.
你看起来准备好了
You look ready.
准备好面对什么 无秩序
Ready for what? Anarchy?
过道一片混乱
Chaos in the corridors?
还是像沙丁鱼一样堆放的冰冻尸体
Frozen bodies stacked up like sardines
因为肥料室都忙不过来了
because compost can't keep up,
而你却从容地回到火车头
while you just swan off to the Engine,
躲避你造成的这一切
hide from everything that you've wrought?
是啊 把我丢在这应付这些...
Oh, yeah, leave me here with these...
人
people?
安德烈·莱顿的代表理事会
Andre Layton's Council of Representatives?
-这是重新开始 露丝  -这绝对行不通
-It's a clean slate, Ruth.  -It's never gonna work.
民主以前就行得通
Democracy used to work.
有时 有些东西必须失去过才能再找回来
Sometimes you have to lose something to find it again.
你把147个人送到外面等死
You put 147 people out there to die.
其中有很多都是我的朋友
Many of them my friends.
包括诺兰·格雷
Including Nolan Grey.
那么...
Well...
生存不需要爱 对吗
Survival doesn't need love, does it?
我之前想错了
That's what I got so wrong.
爱是最重要的
There's nothing more important than love.
回头见 露丝
I'll see you around, Ruth.
我们已经道过别了
We've already said our goodbyes.
-你在三角测量吗  -我正在测
-You triangulating it?  -I'm trying.
本 信号指向西北方
Ben, the signal's reading to the northwest.
西北方
Northwest?
拜托 哈维 外面什么都没有
Come on, Javi. There's nothing out there.
我回来了
Hey. I'm back.
你这身打扮真好看
That's a good look on you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我们会在19:30经过芝加哥
Okay, so, we'll be passing through Chicago at 19:30,
像往常一样把速度降下来 来标记起始点
slowing her down as usual to mark Mile Zero.
梅 梅
Mel, Mel.
听听这个
Listen to this.
音乐
Music?
如果这台老旧收音机都能收到
If that old radio picked it up,
肯定来源于列车内部
it's probably just something from us.
听我说 这信号来自于西北方
Guys, listen to me. It's coming from the northwest.
在外面
Outside.
Outside?
天啊
Jesus.
幸存者
Survivors?
接收器的距离是多长
That receiver's range is what?
最长80公里吗
80 kilometers max?
本 外面有什么
Ben, what's out there?
卫星链接断了 我正在处理
Satellite link's down. I'm working on it.
该死 方向天线也冻住了
Damn it. Directional antenna froze, too.
我无法找到第二个点来三角测量
I can't get a second point to triangulate.
真的吗
Seriously?
我正在处理 梅
I'm on it, Mel. I'm on it.
但这个信号越来越强
But that signal is still getting stronger,
这意味着我们离它越来越近
and that means we're getting closer.
如果我们不减速的话
If we don't slow down,
我们马上就会驶出接收范围
we're gonna be out of range in no time.
我把莱顿叫过来
I'm gonna get Layton up here.
梅 我们不用经过莱顿的批准
Mel, we don't need to go through Layton.
本 需要经他批准
Yes, Ben, we do.
这是辆全新的列车
It's a new train.
有着全新的指挥链
It's a new chain of command.
打扰一下 莱顿先生
Excuse me. Mr. Layton?
我抓到这两个人想
I caught these two trying to smuggle
把生菜偷拿去前车
a cart full of lettuce uptrain.
车就在那里 老大
The cart was just there, boss.
别跟我这么说话
Hey, look, don't gimme that shit.
你打算拿到哪去
Where were you taking it?
派克接管了头等厢 买卖脏物
Pike's set up in First, fencing stuff.
派克
Pike.
一位擅自主张的车尾人 想象一下
A rogue Tailie. Imagine that.
安德烈·莱顿请到火车头
Andre Layton to the Engine.
安德烈·莱顿请马上到火车头
Andre Layton to the Engine immediately.
现在怎么办
Now what?
我不知道 把他关禁闭吧
I don't know. Put them in lockup, okay?
禁闭室满员了 先生
The lockups are full, sir.
在我回来之前尽力维持秩序
Well, do something and keep order until I get back.
生菜
Lettuce.
"秩序"
"Order".
听上去是那么的熟悉 对吗
Yeah, it's got a familiar ring to it, doesn't it?
好的 走吧 小兔子们
Alright, let's go, bunny rabbits.
我们走
Let's go!
幸存者 这有可能吗
Survivors? Is that even possible?
也许吧
Maybe.
但自从我们上一次接到无线电信号
But it's been six and a half years
已经有六年半了
since we've had a radio contact.
谁能像这样坚持下来
Who could hold out like that?
军队吗 私人地堡吗
Military? A private bunker?
肯定是一座老塔 一个回路
It's gotta be an old tower, a loop,
某种备份
some sort of backup.
为什么我们之前从来没有听到过
Why haven't we heard it before?
我们从没用过无线电 没有可以联系的人
We never use the radio. There's no one to talk to.
我们的卫星图像在哪 本
Where's our sat pic, Ben?
我正在恢复
I'm working on it.
我无法确定来源 但信号正变得越来越强
I can't pinpoint it, but the signal keeps getting stronger.
本
Ben?
请说 这里是雪国列车 你能听到吗
Come in. This is Snowpiercer. Do you copy?
我们需要更多时间 梅
We need more time, Mel.
我们的时间不够用了
We're running out of that.
你能听到吗 再重复一遍
Do you copy? I repeat.
速度再放慢一些 试着获取图像
Let's slow further. Let's try and get a visual.
问题在这儿
Here's the call.
如果降低速度 我们就会出现短缺
If we take speed off, we'll be in deficit,
消耗掉多于我们所生产的能量
using more power than we can generate.
我们已经快接近应急能量储存线了
We're already near emergency reserves,
而我们想放慢速度经过芝加哥
and we want to slow to go through Chicago.
另一方面
Now, on the other hand,
如果我们经过这个信号 却没有找到其来源
if we race past this signal without pinpointing it,
那么再次听到它 就要再跑上一整圈
it'll be a full revolution before we can hear it again.
如果可能存在着其他幸存者
If there's a possibility of other survivors,
我们并不孤单 我们就得联系他们
that we're not alone, we have to make contact.
同意 减慢列车速度
Agreed. Slowing the train.
抱歉
Sorry.
别碰我
Get off of me!
停下来
Stop! Oh!
搞什么鬼啊
Bloody hell!
朝我另一边脸也打一拳吧
Take a crack at the other one, at least.
什么
What?
对不起
I'm sorry.
抱歉 只是...
Sorry. Just...
我失去了一切 我的全世界都崩塌了
I've lost everything, and my whole world is gone.
而且大家都恨我
And everyone hates me.
别担心 大家也都恨我
Don't worry. Everyone hates me, too.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我们和好了吗
Are we good?
车尾人把我从头等厢赶出来了
Tailies threw me out of First.
没人愿意帮助我
And no one would help me.
我没有任何可以用来交换的东西了 除了
And I don't even have anything left to trade except...
这个可是好东西
That's not nothing.
看
Look.
我从三等厢餐厅里偷来的
I stole it from the mess hall.
我们怎么才能把蛋壳剥了啊
Well, how are we even supposed to take the skin off?
你不知道怎么剥鸡蛋吗
You don't know how to peel an egg?
天啊 这很好笑 抱歉
Oh my... Well, that's funny. Sorry.
我来给你演示一下
Come on. Let me show you.
拿过来吧 小可爱 没事的
Come on, love. You're alright.
我也是个坏蛋
I'm a bad egg, too.
信号在达到峰值 我们应该快要遇到它了
Signal's peaking. We should be almost on top of it.
马上就会出现画面了
Should have visual any second now.
我的上帝啊
Oh, my God.
所有人 请...
Um, everybody, please...
露丝 露丝
Ruth! Ruth!
外面出现了另一辆列车
Th-There's another train out there.
露丝 发生了什么
Ruth? Wh-What's happening?
还有其他人活着吗
Are there other people alive?
借过 借过
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
露丝 外面还有人活着吗
Ruth, are there people alive out there?
是的 在那里
Yes. There.
你看
Look.
我的老天
Sweet Jimmeny.
他现在掌控补给列车
He's running the supply train.
你不能确定是他 梅
You don't know it's him, Mel.
等等 有补给列车吗
Wait. There's a supply train?
-大爱丽丝  -谁
-It's Big Alice.  -Who?
大爱丽丝 是引擎原型
Big Alice. She's a prototype Engine.
-梅兰妮  -我要全速前进
-Melanie?  -I'm going to full speed.
-能用上的全都给我  -我会的
-Give me everything we have.  -I will.
那条支线是相连的 梅
That spur connects, Mel.
不管是谁 他们都会开到我们后面
Whoever it is, they're gonna switch in behind us.
是他
It's Him.
梅兰妮 和我说说
Melanie, talk to me.
他会想上登上我们的火车
He's gonna try and board us.
你怎么知道是他 梅
You don't know it's Him, Mel.
还会是谁 本
Who else, Ben?
难道又是方舟海盗吗
Another merry band of ark pirates?
-你是说...  -你是说威尔福德吗
-What are you talk---You mean Wilford?
-什么  -没错
-What?!  -Yes.
威尔福德先生回来了
Mr. Wilford is back!
大家都冷静点 太好了
Everybody just stay calm! Yeah!
如果威尔福德真的上了车
If Wilford does board us,
我们的处境
we're in for something far worse
就会比刚刚经历过得更糟糕
than anything we've just come through.
那我会在列车后方组个作战队
Then I'll get a war party downtrain
确保不会出现这种情况
and make sure that doesn't happen.
莱顿 等乘客发现是他时
Layton. When the passengers realize it's Him,
他们会产生分歧的
they'll be divided.
我能让大家团结一致
I can keep us together.
你必须做到
You have to.
露丝 别说了 我们刚刚证实他已经死了
Ruth, stop. We just confirmed that He was dead.
这是不可能的
It's not possible.
还有谁能幸存下来
Who else could survive?
回答我
Answer me that.
他回来是要把我们从叛军手中解救出来
He's back to save us from these bloody rebels.
特里斯坦 我们要办一个欢迎会
Tristan, we're gonna need a greeting party.
欢迎会
Greeting party?
糟了 规章不允许这样吗
No. Is that not the protocol?
我不记得了
I can't remember.
没事 我们会将就点
Never mind. We'll make do.
好 你去梳洗一下
Okay, you tidy yourself up.
我们现在要去车尾
We're going to The Tail.
是的 长官
Yes, ma'am.
梅 我们消耗了太多储存能量
Mel, we're pulling way too much from the banks.
距离是多少
What's our distance?
妈的 他们要跟车尾对接了
Shit. She's gonna dock with The Tail.
所以他们要刹车
That's why they're hitting the brakes.
该死的 他怎么回来了
Damn it. What is He doing back?
梅 你要想清楚后果
Mel, you have to consider the outcomes.
爱丽丝是一辆大火车
Alice is a big train.
四十节车厢对它来说不算什么
40 cars is nothing for her.
但是它是地转动火车 我们可以跑得比它快
But she's low-torqued. We can outrun Him.
-数学证明它会赶上我们  -那就再看一次
-The math says He'll catch us. Then look again.
你能找到的电流 我都要需要 哈维
I need every amp you can find, Javi,
从农业区或是任何地方抽取
from Ag-Sec, from anywhere.
-拜托 梅  -去试一下
-Come on, Mel.  -Just try.
我们必须试试
We have to try.
就快达到转接口
Nearly at the switch.
它在我们后面开来
It's coming in behind us.
快点 各位 你们要错过这场世界盛事了
Come on, guys. You're missing out on world events here!
派对结束了 出去 快
Alright, party's over. Get out of here. Go.
快出去
Come on! Out!
出去
Clear out!
-你 坐下  -出去 出去
-You. Sit down.  -Go. Get out of here. Go.
快
Come on!
-好  -谁能不爱民主啊
-Okay.  -Don't you just love democracy?
在民主世界里你得参与 派克
You gotta participate in a democracy, Pike.
快 现在是你的机会
Come on. Now's your chance.
后面那人是我想的那人吗
Is that who I think it is behind us?
如果是的话 那这一切还没开始
Yeah, well, if it is, then all of this might be over
可能就会结束了 快点
before it even starts, so come on.
我需要所有人团结起来对付共同的敌人
I need everybody united together against a common enemy.
莱顿 你为什么总是要我做一个更好的人
Layton, why do you got to always ask me to be a better man?
-把他拉起来  -走
-Get him up.  -Let's go.
这该死的列车
God damn this train.
我刚开始觉得有乐子了
You know, I was just starting to have some fun here.
我们开往芝加哥的速度太快
We're coming too hard to go into Chicago.
储存能源到达紧急水平了
Reserves are at emergency.
要是用完 我们就完了 我要放慢速度
If we dry it out, it's over. I'm pulling her back.
不行 这是命令
No! That's an order!
他就在我们后面
He's right behind us!
差点让车尾脱节
Almost took off the bloody Tail!
散开
Hey! Break it up!
散开 这是紧急事件
Hey! Break it up! It's an emergency!
拜托 莱顿 威尔福德怎么可能回来
Come on, Layton. How can Wilford be back?
不管是谁 他们都想登上我们的列车 好吗
Whoever it is, they are boarding us, okay?
我们的车尾 我有15个司闸员
Our Tail! Now, I got 15 Brakemen.
-我需要更多士兵  -还在等什么
-I need more soldiers.  -What are we waiting for?
-我们走  -走
-Let's go.  -Let's go.
其余的人 你们懂规矩
Okay, everybody else, you know the drill.
在上下都设置障碍 准备把门焊接上
Barricades above and below! Be ready to weld the doors.
听我指挥 去车尾
On me. To The Tail.
走
Let's go!
快啊
Come on, girl.
保持距离
Just keep your distance.
拜托
Come on.
温妮 小心
Uh, Winnie, be careful.
什么声音
Whoa. What was that?
-你们还好吗  -我好怕
-Are you guys okay?  -I'm scared.
我的天
Oh, my God.
各位 他们想要连接上行线
Come on, guys. They're trying to uplink.
他们要侵入了 他会占领系统
They're hacking in. He'll seize the system.
他会占领火车头 他在拖慢我们
He'll seize the Engine. He's slowing us down.
我要下线所有非关键系统
I'm taking non-critical systems offline.
我们得出去
We gotta go outside.
那太疯狂了
Come on. That's crazy.
必须切断上行线
Gotta cut the uplink.
哈维 你能拖住他吗
Javi, can you hold Him off?
-拖不了太久 梅  -好
-Not for long, Mel.  -Okay.
那我们最好加紧了
Then we better hurry.
列车交给你了 我们走
You have the train. Let's go.
你们退后
You guys fall back now, okay?
那要不了多久
That won't take long.
把这些床拖到后面去
These bunks, back 'em up, alright?
我们需要空间
We're gonna need space.
♪ Lift up your hearts And give praise with our song ♪
* 为了威尔福德先生 我们的呼声会很强烈 *
* For Mr. Wilford, our cry will be strong *
♪ For Mr. Wilford Our cry will be strong ♪
♪ Rising above Your mind's aim is true ♪
* 名字是真的 *
* ...name is true *
* 欢呼雀跃 因为我们尊敬你 *
* Cheer and rejoice, for we honor you *
♪ Cheer and rejoice For we honor you ♪
♪ Lift up your voice Though the path may be long ♪
* 提高嗓门 尽管路可能很长 *
* Lift up your voice, though the path may be long *
露丝
Ruth.
Ruth!
* 永远不会错 *
* ...will never be wrong *
露丝 少胡来
Ruth, cut the crap!
我是来办公的 罗切先生
I am here officially, Mr. Roche.
根据规定 乘客服务部引导欢迎派对
Hospitality leads the welcoming party, as per protocol.
我们现在处于军事状态 露丝
We're in a military situation here, Ruth.
你得带这些孩子出去
You got to get these kids out of here.
他们要闯进我们的列车了
They are breaching the goddamn train!
退后 退后 大家退后
Okay, back up! Back up! Everybody back!
我是高官
I'm a dignitary.
我感觉到了
Yeah, I feel that.
诺兰·格雷本可以穿着制服站在这里
Nolan Grey would have been here in his full dress uniform.
我本可以站在他身旁
And I would have been right beside him
因为我的制服是和平的体现
because my uniform says peace.
这或许是你的民主实验 莱顿先生
Now, this may be your democratic experiment, Mr. Layton,
但我是乘客服务部的老大
but I am Head of Hospitality.
蓝绿色是外交的颜色
And teal is the color of diplomacy.
放下武器
Weapons down.
所有人放下武器
Everybody, put your weapons down.
放下
Put them down.
你是对的
You're right.
你是对的 外交放在首位
You're right. Diplomacy first, right?
没人想再经历一次战争
Nobody wants another war.
当那道门打开后 我要你站在我身旁
When that door opens, I want you right by my side.
我需要你 准备和谈
I need you there, ready to parlay,
同时展现武力 作为支撑
with a show of force to back us up.
同意吗
Agreed?
我想到最前面去
I want to be right up there, in the front.
我想要第一个和他握手
And I want to be the first one to shake His hand.
嗯 必须是你
Yes. It has to be you.
把枪给他 露丝
Give him the gun, Ruth.
好了 把这些小孩带去安全的地方
Okay. Alright, get these kids somewhere safe.
露丝 跟我到前面去
Ruth, come up front with me.
我们到上面 以钩钩住
Okay, we pop the top, hook in,
进入车尾
make our way to The Tail.
然后用手切断上行线
Then we cut the uplink by hand.
这是个乱套的计划 梅
It's a haywire plan, Mel.
你有更好的主意吗
Yeah, well, you got a better one?
因为他会拖慢我们的速度 冻死我们
'Cause he's gonna peel off our speed and freeze us out.
或许我们该让步
Then maybe we have to stand down.
拜托
Come on.
你有想过那辆补给列车上有什么吗
Have you thought about what's on that supply train?
有想过
Yeah, I have.
因为我们需要它 梅
'Cause we need her, Mel.
雪国列车快要分崩离析了
Snowpiercer is coming apart.
你知道的
You know it.
没有永动
There is no perpetual motion
因为没有永恒的零件
because there are no perpetual parts.
但是那辆补给列车上有很多
But that supply train is packed  --
转向车发动机 牛培养菌 一个完整的基因实验室
bogie motors, bovine cultures, a full genetics lab.
足以让我们继续行驶下去
Enough to keep us going.
你怎么知道什么东西还在
How do you know what's still there?
已经快七年了
It's been almost seven years.
你知道还剩什么
How do you know what's left?
或者他们建立了怎样的社会
Or what kind of society they've made?
或者他们有怎样的疾病
Or what kind of diseases they carry?
即使他们有我们所需的一切
And even if they have everything that we need,
他会想要什么作为回报
what'll He want in return?
你早知道他在那
You knew He was there.
-我知道你会逃跑  -你知道多久了
-I knew you would run.  -How long did you know?
我今早在卫星上看到他们
I saw them on the satellite this morning,
但我立刻就知道是他了
but I knew it was Him right away.
-所以你切断了信号  -是的
-So you killed the feed.  -Yeah.
你让我们和他相遇
You steered us right into him!
我们本可以逃避的
We could have evaded!
最重要的是
And more importantly,
你和我本可以一起做那个决定
you and I could have made that choice together!
你做了一个单方面的决定
You made a unilateral move.
现在该我了
Here's mine.
搞什么 梅
What the hell, Mel?!
我不会再把我的命运交到威尔福德手中
I will not put my faith in Wilford again,
所以我要出去解放列车
so I am going out there to free the helm.
无论如何
And one way or another...
你都要在我离开期间保持方舟的运行
you're gonna keep this ark going when I'm gone.
-别这样 梅  -放我走
-Don't do this, Mel.  -You let me go.
我们在另一头见
I'll see you on the other side.
哈维 她一个人出去了
Javi, she went out alone.
我阻止不了她
I couldn't stop her.
冲
Vamos.
冲啊
刹车
Brakes.
我们被截停了
We're stopped.
我们有多久时间
How long have we got?
大概十分钟
10 minutes, give or take.
雪国列车 不管谁在那道门后面
Snowpiercer, no matter who is on the other side of that door,
记住一点
remember this  --
-威尔福德只是个凡人  -一个伟人
-Wilford was only ever a man.  -A great man.
不要在你脑海里把他想成别的
Do not build him up in your minds into something He isn't.
他不是你的工程师
He is not your Engineer.
这不是他的列车
This is not His train.
我想你会发现这就是他的
I think you'll find that it is.
雪国列车是我们的
Snowpiercer is ours!
它属于它的公民
She belongs to her citizens!
-没错  -没错
-Yeah!  -That's right!
你是谁
Who are you?
我们得发动我们的列车
We need to get our train moving.
雪国列车向你问好 威尔福德先生在车上吗
Greetings from Snowpiercer. Is Mr. Wilford aboard?
威尔福德先生已经控制了你们的引擎
Mr. Wilford has already seized control of your engine.
你们有13分钟同意和平投降
You have about 13 minutes to agree to a peaceful surrender
不然寒冷袭来 你们都将冻死
before the cold overcomes and you all freeze to death.
告诉他我们需要见到他本人
Tell Him we need to see Him face-to-face.
同意 我们欢迎他上车
Please, yes, and that we welcome him aboard.
-你是乘客服务部的  -是的
-You're Hospitality?  -I am, yes.
我叫露丝·沃德尔 听候吩咐
My name's Ruth Wardle, at your service.
梅兰妮·卡维尔还活着吗
Is Melanie Cavill alive?
是的 她还活着
Yes. Yes, she is.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫艾莉珊德拉·卡维尔
My name is Alexandra Cavill.
艾莉珊德拉
Alexandra?
我妈妈在哪
Where is my mother?